Professor Richard Jonas Papers, 1990-1992
University of Houston Libraries
Professor Richard Jonas Collection
1934-1986
Special Collections, University of Houston Libraries
Jonas, Richard
11.00 Linear Feet
The original order of the Professor Richard Jonas Papers has been maintained where possible. The collection includes limited correspondence, brochures and directories that relate to health, welfare and various community-related agencies. Most of the materials in the collection date from 1934 to 1978 with the majority dating from the 1950s. Items in the collection relating to the university include the Guidance Office, job evaluation manual, the library, the proposed College of Philosophy and Religion and U.H. veterans. The collection also includes a small portion of personal correspondence, which may provide background information and perspective to the researcher.
1969-025
Biographical Note
Richard O. Jonas (1898-1983) received a BA from the University of Texas in 1920, an MA from the University of Texas in 1923 and completed all advanced graduate work for the Ph.D., except a dissertation. Jonas was Professor of Psychology and Education and the Director of Guidance at Wichita Falls Junior College from 1922 to 1942. He came to the University of Houston in 1944 as Associate Professor of Psychology and Chief Counselor, continuing in this capacity until 1947. From 1947 to 1951, he served as Professor of Psychology and Director of Guidance and from 1951 to 1956 as Professor of Psychology and Consultant in Guidance. In 1956, Jonas became Research Professor of Psychology.
Scope and Contents
The original order of the Professor Richard Jonas Papers has been maintained where possible. The collection includes limited correspondence, brochures and directories that relate to health, welfare and various community-related agencies. Most of the materials in the collection date from 1934 to 1978 with the majority dating from the 1950s. Items in the collection relating to the university include the Guidance Office, job evaluation manual, the library, the proposed College of Philosophy and Religion and U.H. veterans. The collection also includes a small portion of personal correspondence, which may provide background information and perspective to the researcher.
Forms part of the University Archives.
Index Terms
This Collection is indexed under the following controlled access subject terms.
Corporate Name:
University of Houston. Psychology Dept.; University of Houston
Genre/Form of Material:
Brochures; Correspondence; Personal papers
Personal Name:
Jonas, Richard O.
Access Restrictions
Open for research.
Acquisition
Detailed Description
- Conferences, 1955-1969
  This series consists of eight folders, arranged alphabetically. The majority of these contain brochures, bulletins or handouts from various conferences or symposia. The folders date from 1955 to 1969.
  - American Petroleum Institute, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Conference in Latin America, 1967-1969 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Conference on Rehabilitation Therapy V.A. Hospital, April 7, 1956 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - National Association Retarded Children, 6th Convention Houston, 1955 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - National Resources Conference (Houston, TX), September 19-30, 1955 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Southern State Work Conference, 1955-1956 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Statement to the Texas Commission on Higher Education by Paul E. Purser, 1962 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - WRENN Symposium, June 10-14, 1957 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Organizations/Associations 1945-1957
  This series consists of eighteen folders of brochures, bulletins, newsletters and limited correspondence related to different organizations and associations. Folders are arranged alphabetically and date from 1945 to 1957.
  - American Association of University Professors, 1956 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Association of Texas Colleges, 1955 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Directory, Community Council of Houston and Harris Counties, 1952-1953 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Health, Welfare, and Recreation Agencies of Houston and Harris County, 1953 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Information for American Psychological Association, 1956 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Junior College, 1955 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Junior College Office, 1952-1955 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Phi Delta Kappa, 1946-1951 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - South Texas Counselors Association Constitution, 1950-1954 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Southwest Regional Basic Institute on Hospital Personnel Management, 1945 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Southwest Regional Orientation Institute for Rehabilitation Personnel, 1953-1955 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Student Council Workshop of Texas, 1956 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Texas Commission for the Blind-Texas Education Agency, 1952-1954 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Texas Council on Family Relations, 1954-1956 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Texas Junior College Association, 1951 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Texas Personnel and Management Association, 1951-1956 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Texas Personnel and Management Association, 1953-1957 (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Vocational Guidance Kit:American Optometric Program, 1955-1957 (Box 1, Folder 26)
- University Related
  This series is the largest, consisting of 366 folders dating from 1934 to 1986. The materials in this series cover a wide range of university-related topics and it is divided into five sub-series: Administration, Other UH Campuses, Academics, Student Activities and Groups, and Faculty and Staff Activities andGroups. Each sub-series is arranged alphabetically. Due to the positions Jonas held at the university, the folders related to the Guidance Office, library and the Veterans Office contain the most material.
  - Administration
    - Academic Advising, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - Academic Honesty Policy, 1948-1970 (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - Admissions - Graduate, 1977-1983 (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - Admissions - Undergraduate, 1978 (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - Admissions Office, 1963-1964 (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - Admissions Policies, 1955-1963 (Box 2, Folder 6)
    - Advisory Board, By-laws, 1943 (Box 2, Folder 7)
    - Air Age Workshop for Educators, 1950-1951 (Box 2, Folder 8)
    - Alumni Association, 1953-1981 (Box 2, Folder 9)
    - Alumni Association-from Sabu, October 1953 (Box 2, Folder 10)
    - American Federation for Teachers, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 11)
    - American Red Cross Blood Program, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 12)
    - Annual Lecture Series in Psychology, 1952-1953 (Box 2, Folder 13)
    - Blue Cross-Blue Shield Hospitalization Program, 1970 (Box 2, Folder 14)
    - Board of Governors, December 7, 1956 (Box 2, Folder 15)
    - Board of Regents, November 8, 1978 (Box 2, Folder 16)
    - Board of Trustees, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 17)
    - Booklets, 1945-1978 (Box 2, Folder 18)
    - Brochures, 1952-1978 (Box 2, Folder 19)
    - Campus, 1968 (Box 2, Folder 20)
    - Campus Newspapers, 1968 (Box 2, Folder 21)
    - Career Planning and Placement, 1966-1980 (Box 2, Folder 22)
    - Christmas, 1947-1951 (Box 2, Folder 23)
    - Citizenship and Career Conference, 1952-1955 (Box 2, Folder 24)
    - Civil Defense, 1962 (Box 2, Folder 25)
    - College of Business; Alumni, September 2, 1982 (Box 2, Folder 26)
    - Committee on Improvement of Nursing Services, 1952-1953 (Box 2, Folder 27)
    - Committee on Clerical Personnel Practices, 1950-1951 (Box 2, Folder 28)
    - Committee on Faculty Personnel and Organization, 1946 (Box 2, Folder 29)
    - Committee on Guidance, 1943 (Box 2, Folder 30)
    - Community Action Seminar, 1966-1967 (Box 2, Folder 31)
    - Comparative Data, 1947-1949 (Box 2, Folder 32)
    - Comparative Enrollment, 1945-1948 (Box 2, Folder 33)
    - Conference on Exceptional Children and Youth, 1978 (Box 2, Folder 34)
    - Controller, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 35)
    - Cooperative Educational Program, 1948-1950 (Box 2, Folder 36)
    - Cooperative Industrial Personnel Testing Institute, 1952 (Box 2, Folder 37)
    - Coordinating Board, 1971-1973 (Box 2, Folder 38)
    - Correspondence, 1954-1960 (Box 2, Folder 39)
    - Counseling and Testing Service, 1942-1970 (Box 2, Folder 40)
    - Counselors' Conference, 1953-1974 (Box 2, Folder 41)
    - Cullen, Ezekiel W. Building, 1950 (Box 2, Folder 42)
    - Cullen, Hugh Roy, 1957 (Box 2, Folder 43)
    - Curriculum, 1949-1969 (Box 2, Folder 44)
    - Curriculum - Objective, 1953 (Box 2, Folder 45)
    - Dana, John Cotton Publicity Award, 1971-1972 (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - Dean of Men, n.d. (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - Dean of Women, 1964 (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - Dean of Student Affairs, 1972 (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - Deans Associate and Assistant, 1977-1982 (Box 3, Folder 5)
    - De Hartog, Jan, 1968 (Box 3, Folder 6)
    - Development Office, 1967-1972 (Box 3, Folder 7)
    - Doctoral Level Semester Credit Hours, 1967 (Box 3, Folder 8)
    - Downtown School, 1963-1966 (Box 3, Folder 9)
    - Driver Education, 1962 (Box 3, Folder 10)
    - Dudley, Mrs. Roy L., 1971 (Box 3, Folder 11)
    - Enrollment, 1934-1945 (Box 3, Folder 12)
    - Enrollment, 1945-1946 (Box 3, Folder 13)
    - Enrollment, 1947 (Box 3, Folder 14)
    - Enrollment, 1947-1949 (Box 3, Folder 15)
    - Enrollment, 1947-1949 (Box 3, Folder 16)
    - Enrollment, 1948-1949 (Box 3, Folder 17)
    - Enrollment, 1949-1950 (Box 3, Folder 18)
    - Enrollment, 1950 (Box 3, Folder 19)
    - Enrollment, 1951 (Box 3, Folder 20)
    - Enrollment, 1957 (Box 3, Folder 21)
    - Enrollment, 1958 (Box 3, Folder 22)
    - Enrollment, 1959 (Box 3, Folder 23)
    - Enrollment, 1960 (Box 3, Folder 24)
    - Enrollment, 1961 (Box 3, Folder 25)
    - Enrollment, 1964 (Box 3, Folder 26)
    - Enrollment, 1965 (Box 3, Folder 27)
    - Enrollment, 1970 (Box 3, Folder 28)
    - Ethnic Affairs, 1969-1986 (Box 3, Folder 29)
    - Examinations, 1953 (Box 3, Folder 30)
    - Excellence Campaign, n.d. (Box 3, Folder 31)
    - Executive Council, 1950 (Box 3, Folder 32)
    - Ex-Students Association, 1947-1954 (Box 3, Folder 33)
    - General Statistics, 1955-1959 (Box 3, Folder 34)
    - Graduate Council, 1952-1954 (Box 3, Folder 35)
    - Graduate School - Faculty Nominations, 1967 (Box 3, Folder 36)
    - Graduate Semester Credit Hours, 1966-1967 (Box 3, Folder 37)
    - Guidance Conference, 1954, 1954-1956 (Box 4, Folder 1)
    - Guidance Office, 1947-1950 (Box 4, Folder 2)
    - Guidance Office, 1951-1953 (Box 4, Folder 3)
    - Guidance Office - Basic Data Forms, n.d. (Box 4, Folder 4)
    - Guidance Office - Job Analysis, 1947 (Box 4, Folder 5)
    - Guidance Office - Publicity, 1948-1956 (Box 4, Folder 6)
    - Guidance Project, 1948-1949 (Box 4, Folder 7)
    - Gulf School Research Development Association, 1964-1970 (Box 4, Folder 8)
    - Haynes, Robert, 1976 (Box 4, Folder 9)
    - High School Administrators Dinner, 1956 (Box 4, Folder 10)
    - High school and College Programs, Conference, 1958-1972 (Box 4, Folder 11)
    - Health Center, n.d. (Box 4, Folder 12)
    - Human relations Committee, 1967-1969 (Box 4, Folder 13)
    - Inkblot", 1958 (Box 4, Folder 14)
    - Institute for College Recruitment Interviewing, 1957 (Box 4, Folder 15)
    - Institutional Advancement, March 23, 1979 (Box 4, Folder 16)
    - Insurance (Employee), 1944-1971 (Box 4, Folder 17)
    - Inter University Correspondence, 1951-1960 (Box 4, Folder 18)
    - Job Evaluation Committee, 1950-1951 (Box 4, Folder 19)
    - Job Evaluation Manual, 1951 (Box 4, Folder 20)
    - Journalism - Student Publication, 1949-1962 (Box 4, Folder 21)
    - Junior High School Conference, 1954 (Box 4, Folder 22)
    - Kittinger, William Townes, Memorial Service, October 7, 1970 (Box 4, Folder 23)
    - "The Kougar Klaw,", 1961 (Box 4, Folder 24)
    - KUHT, 1953-1954 (Box 4, Folder 25)
    - Lab Nursery School, Department of Home Economics, 1971 (Box 4, Folder 26)
    - Lamar Fleming Building - Dedication, 1965 (Box 4, Folder 27)
    - Library, 1955-1961 (Box 4, Folder 28)
    - Library Committee Meeting Minutes, 1968-1971 (Box 4, Folder 29)
    - Library Miscellaneous, 1950-1969 (Box 4, Folder 30)
    - Library Staff Association Education Committee Workshop on Presentation Binding, 1974 (Box 4, Folder 31)
    - Library Staff Association Minutes, 1972-1973 (Box 4, Folder 32)
    - Library Staff Association Newsletter, 1972-1975 (Box 4, Folder 33)
    - Library Staff Evaluation for Self-Study, 1965 (Box 4, Folder 34)
    - Mission Self-Study, 1970s (Box 4, Folder 35)
    - Navy Mother's Club of America, n.d. (Box 4, Folder 36)
    - Oberholtzer Hall, 1951 (Box 4, Folder 37)
    - Occupational Planning Commission, 1948 (Box 4, Folder 38)
    - Office of the Chancellor, 1957-1984 (Box 4, Folder 39)
    - Office of the Dean, 1970-1984 (Box 4, Folder 40)
    - Organizations Board, 1971 (Box 4, Folder 41)
    - Ostrofsky, 1978 (Box 4, Folder 42)
    - Ostrofsky, 1978 (Box 4, Folder 43)
    - Parents and Friends Society, 1958-1959 (Box 5, Folder 1)
    - Part Time Staff, n.d. (Box 5, Folder 2)
    - Payroll Office, 1946-1980 (Box 5, Folder 3)
    - Personal Correspondence, 1949-1972 (Box 5, Folder 4)
    - Personnel, 1978 (Box 5, Folder 5)
    - Personnel Psychological Services Center, 1953-1971 (Box 5, Folder 6)
    - Personal Services - Employee Benefits, October 1970 (Box 5, Folder 7)
    - Personnel Services Office, 1967-1970 (Box 5, Folder 8)
    - Personnel Services Office Employment Bulletin, 1969-1980 (Box 5, Folder 9)
    - Placement Center, 1947-1975 (Box 5, Folder 10)
    - Placement Center Employment Reports, 1959 (Box 5, Folder 11)
    - Placement Center-Reports, 1957-1962 (Box 5, Folder 12)
    - Position of Rank, Fall 1967 (Box 5, Folder 13)
    - Postal Services, 1971 (Box 5, Folder 14)
    - Press Releases, 1971 (Box 5, Folder 15)
    - Printing Plant, 1963 (Box 5, Folder 16)
    - Projects, February 1978 (Box 5, Folder 17)
    - Proposal for Full State Support, 1963 (Box 5, Folder 18)
    - Proposals, n.d. (Box 5, Folder 19)
    - Psychological Services Center, 1945-1952 (Box 5, Folder 20)
    - Purchasing Agent, 1947-1981 (Box 5, Folder 21)
    - Reading Conference, 1952-1969 (Box 5, Folder 22)
    - Real Estate, 1976 (Box 5, Folder 23)
    - Real Estate, 1976 (Box 5, Folder 24)
    - Registration, 1945-1949 (Box 5, Folder 25)
    - Registration, 1949-1955 (Box 5, Folder 26)
    - Registration, 1956-1975 (Box 5, Folder 27)
    - Reorganization, Study Group, 1973 (Box 5, Folder 28)
    - Reports, 1939-1944 (Box 5, Folder 29)
    - Scholastic Requirements, 1946, 1955 (Box 5, Folder 30)
    - Special Student Services, Veterans and Handicap, 1978-1982 (Box 5, Folder 31)
    - Special Reports, 1938-1946 (Box 5, Folder 32)
    - Special Reports, 1949-1950 (Box 5, Folder 33)
    - Sports, 1969 (Box 5, Folder 34)
    - Staff Policies and Procedures, 1976 (Box 6, Folder 1)
    - Staff - Retirement Plan, 1954-1969 (Box 6, Folder 2)
    - Staff - Salaries, 1941-1956 (Box 6, Folder 3)
    - Staff - Tuition Benefits, n.d. (Box 6, Folder 4)
    - State Department of Education, 1942-1948 (Box 6, Folder 5)
    - Statistics, 1934-1939 (Box 6, Folder 6)
    - Statistics, 1941-1946 (Box 6, Folder 7)
    - Statistics Enrollment, 1939-1944 (Box 6, Folder 8)
    - Strengthening Cooperative Leadership, July 12, 1979 (Box 6, Folder 9)
    - Student Legal Counseling, 1971 (Box 6, Folder 10)
    - Student Life Division, n.d. (Box 6, Folder 11)
    - Taylor, Leslie, 1957 (Box 6, Folder 12)
    - Teacher Load Report, 1940-1941 (Box 6, Folder 13)
    - Teacher Load Report, 1947 (Box 6, Folder 14)
    - Teacher Load Report, 1947-1948 (Box 6, Folder 15)
    - Teacher Load Report, 1948-1949 (Box 6, Folder 16)
    - Teacher Load Report, 1949-1950 (Box 6, Folder 17)
    - Teacher Load Report, 1950 (Box 6, Folder 18)
    - Tenure and Promotion, 1973 (Box 6, Folder 19)
    - Texas Chapter -Special Libraries Association, 1970-1971 (Box 6, Folder 20)
    - "This Week On Campus", 1972-1973 (Box 6, Folder 21)
    - Town Meeting on Public Education, 1954 (Box 6, Folder 22)
    - University Center, 1967-1969 (Box 6, Folder 23)
    - University Center Groundbreaking and Dedication, 1967 (Box 6, Folder 24)
    - University Club, September 1964 (Box 6, Folder 25)
    - University Council, 1973-1975 (Box 6, Folder 26)
    - University Issues Small Group (College) Reports, Fall 1968 (Box 6, Folder 27)
    - University of Houston - Financial Procedures, 1950-1951 (Box 6, Folder 28)
    - University of Houston - General Staff Meeting, 1972 (Box 6, Folder 29)
    - University of Houston Hour (Radio Program), 1948 (Box 6, Folder 30)
    - University of Houston - Mission Self-Study, 1975 (Box 6, Folder 31)
    - University of Houston - Organization Charts, 1950-1972 (Box 6, Folder 32)
    - University of Houston Society of Accountants, April 15, 1953 (Box 6, Folder 33)
    - University Student Assistance Committee, 1970 (Box 6, Folder 34)
    - Upward Bound, 1978 (Box 6, Folder 35)
    - Vasconcelos, Jos鬠n.d. (Box 6, Folder 36)
    - Veterans, 1946-1957 (Box 6, Folder 37)
    - Vacation Policies, 1946-1948 (Box 6, Folder 38)
    - Wall, Bernhardt, 1949 (Box 6, Folder 39)
    - Werlin, Joseph S. Memorial Scholarship in Sociology, 1964 (Box 6, Folder 40)
  - Other Campuses
    - Clear Lake: Administration, June 17, 1977 (Box 7, Folder 1)
    - Clear Lake: Bayou Building, 1970's (Box 7, Folder 2)
    - Clear Lake: City Center, 1969-1978 (Box 7, Folder 3)
    - Clear Lake: Graduate Center, 1969-1973 (Box 7, Folder 4)
    - Clear Lake: National Aeronautics and Space Inst., 1964-1965 (Box 7, Folder 5)
    - Downtown College: Administration, 1973-1977 (Box 7, Folder 6)
    - Downtown College: Class Schedule, 1946-1949 (Box 7, Folder 7)
    - Downtown College: Class Schedules, 1978-1982 (Box 7, Folder 8)
    - Downtown College: Institute of Retailing, 1973-1975 (Box 7, Folder 9)
    - Downtown College: Inventory of Classes, 1974-1976 (Box 7, Folder 10)
    - Downtown College: Pamphlets, 1950's-1970's (Box 7, Folder 11)
    - Downtown College: Pamphlets, 1970's-1980's (Box 7, Folder 12)
    - Downtown College: Special Services Division (Box 7, Folder 13)
    - Downtown College: "the Downtowner", 1977-1978 (Box 7, Folder 14)
    - Victoria: Administration, September 14, 1972 (Box 7, Folder 15)
    - Victoria: Victoria Center, 1972-1973 (Box 7, Folder 16)
    - Victoria: Victoria Center, 1974 (Box 7, Folder 17)
    - Victoria: Victoria Center, 1975 (Box 7, Folder 18)
    - Victoria: Statistics, 1973-1974 (Box 7, Folder 19)
    - Victoria: Course Inventory, 1975-1977 (Box 7, Folder 20)
    - Victoria: Enrollment, 1974-1977 (Box 7, Folder 21)
    - Victoria: Programs, 1974-1975 (Box 7, Folder 22)
    - Victoria: University Seal (Box 7, Folder 23)
  - Academics
    - Aircrafts and Engines - Training Program, 1946 (Box 8, Folder 1)
    - Art Department, 1946-1947 (Box 8, Folder 2)
    - Art Department, 1952-1969 (Box 8, Folder 3)
    - Center for Study for Democratic Instruction, 1973 (Box 8, Folder 4)
    - Center Study-National Instruction, 1973 (Box 8, Folder 5)
    - College of Religion and Philosophy: Citizens, 1950 (Box 8, Folder 6)
    - College of Religion and Philosophy: Correspondence, 1946-1951 (Box 8, Folder 7)
    - College of Religion and Philosophy: Curriculum, 1950 (Box 8, Folder 8)
    - College of Religion and Philosophy: Endowment (Box 8, Folder 9)
    - College of Religion and Philosophy: Faculty, 1950-1951 (Box 8, Folder 10)
    - College of Religion and Philosophy: Finance, 1950-1953 (Box 8, Folder 11)
    - College of Religion and Philosophy: Prospectus, 1946-1953 (Box 8, Folder 12)
    - College of Technology, 1950 (Box 8, Folder 13)
    - Dale, Edward Everett Award for Teaching (Box 8, Folder 14)
    - Drama Department - L. S. Mitchell, 1936-1960 (Box 8, Folder 15)
    - History Department, 1983-1985 (Box 8, Folder 16)
    - KUHF, 1960 (Box 8, Folder 17)
    - Mathematics Institute, 1950-1951 (Box 8, Folder 18)
    - Photography Department, 1947-1950 (Box 8, Folder 19)
    - Piano Workshop, 1952 (Box 8, Folder 20)
    - Psychology Department, 1945-1959 (Box 8, Folder 21)
    - S.C.O.L.A.S. Newsletter, 1968-1969 (Box 8, Folder 22)
    - Speech Department, 1952 (Box 8, Folder 23)
  - Student Activities and Groups
    - AABL-Afro Americans Black Liberation, 1969 (Box 9, Folder 1)
    - Amateur Radio Club, 1949 (Box 9, Folder 2)
    - Black Student Foundation, 1981 (Box 9, Folder 3)
    - Black Student Union, 1972-1975 (Box 9, Folder 4)
    - Cap amp; Gown, Mortar Board, 1970 (Box 9, Folder 5)
    - Chinese Students Association, 1979-1981 (Box 9, Folder 6)
    - Cougar Club, 1963 (Box 9, Folder 7)
    - Frontier Fiesta, 1956-1959 (Box 9, Folder 8)
    - Harvard Business Club, 1968-1969 (Box 9, Folder 9)
    - Houston Place Action Coalition, 1971 (Box 9, Folder 10)
    - Houstonian Memos, 1959-1973 (Box 9, Folder 11)
    - International Society For Krishna Consciousness (Box 9, Folder 12)
    - Interscholastic League, 1961-1963 (Box 9, Folder 13)
    - Le Quartier Latin, 1945 (Box 9, Folder 14)
    - Libertarian Society, 1963 (Box 9, Folder 15)
    - LOMAS - League Mexican American Students, 1980 (Box 9, Folder 16)
    - Methodist Student Movement, 1947-1951 (Box 9, Folder 17)
    - "Pep Club", 1951 (Box 9, Folder 18)
    - Pre-med Society, 1958 (Box 9, Folder 19)
    - Psychology Club, 1946-1949 (Box 9, Folder 20)
    - Red Masque Players, 1933-1945 (Box 9, Folder 21)
    - Religious Activities, 1952-1970 (Box 9, Folder 22)
    - Rodeo Association, 1963-1964 (Box 9, Folder 23)
    - Rush, 1975, 1975 (Box 9, Folder 24)
    - "Service Sidelights" - Publication of the, 1954-1955 (Box 9, Folder 25)
    - Songfest, 1956 (Box 9, Folder 26)
    - Student Activities, 1959-1964 (Box 9, Folder 27)
    - Student Activities Committee, 1945 (Box 9, Folder 28)
    - Student Activities Conference Southeast Texas, 1955-1981 (Box 9, Folder 29)
    - Student Advisors, 1952 (Box 9, Folder 30)
    - Student Association, 1966-1975 (Box 9, Folder 31)
    - Student Association - Student Course and Teacher Evaluation Program, 1967 (Box 9, Folder 32)
    - Student Association Tutorial Programs (Box 9, Folder 33)
    - Student Education Association, 1958 (Box 9, Folder 34)
    - Student Elections, 1962 (Box 9, Folder 35)
    - Student Government, 1957-1967 (Box 9, Folder 36)
    - Student Humanist Association (Box 9, Folder 37)
    - Students Mobilization Committee (Box 9, Folder 38)
    - Student Opportunity Service, 1970 (Box 9, Folder 39)
    - Student Organizations, 1956-1964 (Box 9, Folder 40)
    - Student Organizations Group Guidelines, 1949-1951 (Box 9, Folder 41)
    - Student Public Committee, 1964-1981 (Box 9, Folder 42)
    - Students for Democratic Society, 1969 (Box 9, Folder 43)
    - Thanksgiving, 1947 (Box 9, Folder 44)
    - "The Third Amphiboly" (Box 9, Folder 45)
    - University of Houston Committee to End War, 1970 (Box 9, Folder 46)
    - University Men's Club, 1951-1982 (Box 9, Folder 47)
    - University Student Assistance Committee (Box 9, Folder 48)
    - University Village Council, 1946-1951 (Box 9, Folder 49)
    - Veterans Club History, 1945-1956 (Box 9, Folder 50)
    - Wesley Foundation, 1957-1959 (Box 9, Folder 51)
    - Women's Liberation Movement, 1970 (Box 9, Folder 52)
    - Women's Students Association, 1955-1967 (Box 9, Folder 53)
    - Young Americans for Freedom, 1970-1971 (Box 9, Folder 54)
    - Young Americans Independent (Box 9, Folder 55)
    - Young Democrats Club, 1963-1970 (Box 9, Folder 56)
    - Young Republicans Club, Jan 1964 (Box 9, Folder 57)
    - Young Socialist Alliance, 1969 (Box 9, Folder 58)
  - Faculty and Staff Activities and Groups
    - American Association of University Professors: Academic Freedom, 1965-1966 (Box 10, Folder 1)
    - American Association of University Professors: Communication, 1965 (Box 10, Folder 2)
    - American Association of University Professors: Convention, 1964 (Box 10, Folder 3)
    - American Association of University Professors: Meeting, 1945 (Box 10, Folder 4)